(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone, welcome back to another
great lesson with us here at English.
Pod, my name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're going out to eat.
- Yes, good thing too, 'cause I'm hungry.
- I know, it's almost lunch time.
- Yeah.
- So today we're gonna be
talking about eating at a restaurant
and giving some great
recommendations and suggestions.
- Yes, we have language
for describing food,
for describing restaurants
and for making suggestions.
- Great, so let's start with our
vocabulary preview for this lesson.
- Vocabulary preview.
- We have two words
today from our dialogue,
which you'll need to know
to understand the dialogue.
- Great.
The first one that we have
today is food poisoning.
- Food poisoning.
- So food poisoning is not a good thing.
- Not a good thing.
- It is when you eat some bad
food and that food makes you sick.
So you get food poisoning.
- Okay, so food poisoning,
yeah, not a good thing.
- Okay, the next words.
- A allergic.
- So when you're allergic to something,
it makes you sick.
That one thing makes you sick.
- Right.
- For example, I'm allergic to seafood.
- If I eat seafood, I cannot breathe.
- Okay, so you definitely
wanna stay away from fish.
- Yes, yes.
- Some people are
allergic to nuts, like peanuts.
- Or maybe milk.
- Milk.
- Yep.
- Cool.
So when one type of food makes
you sick, you are allergic to that food.
- Okay, great.
So with this in mind,
now we can listen to our
dialogue for the first
time at its normal speed,
but don't worry if you don't
get everything now because--
- Welcome back and teach
you the important language.
(upbeat music)
- Are you two have any
plans for the evening?
We were thinking of checking out
a restaurant in the neighborhood.
Do you have any suggestions?
I know there's really nice Italian place.
The food is fantastic
and the decor is beautiful.
I'd recommend giving it a try.
- Actually, I'm not all that
crazy about Italian food.
I'm in the mood for
something a bit lighter.
- In that case, I know
a great little bistro.
They make a really tasty seafood platter.
The fish is outstanding.
It sounds fantastic, but I'm allergic to seafood so...
- Okay, well, let me think.
Oh, I know this great little place.
It's just a hole in the wall,
but they do the most amazing sandwiches.
You can't give them a try.
- Ella, you took me there last time I
visited, and I got food poisoning, remember?
(upbeat music)
- Well, I'm getting hungry, just thinking
about all of those great restaurants.
- Yeah, some really good recommendations
except for food poisoning, I think.
- I know, that's okay.
- Let's start with our language
takeaway for this lesson.
- Language takeaway.
- Our first word on language
takeaway is check out.
- Check out. - Check out.
- Check out.
- So we have some great examples
on how we can use checkout in
different situations, and then
you can understand the meaning.
- Example one.
Have you been to New Cafe next door?
- Yeah, I checked it out yesterday.
The food was great.
- Example two.
- Hey, check out my new car.
- Example three.
- I'm going to check out the
new shopping mall this weekend.
- So I can understand
that it just means look at.
- Yeah, look at, or yeah, or go see.
So let's go check out that new bar in town.
- Yeah, okay, cool.
Next word is.
- Bistro. - Bistro.
- Bistro.
- So what's a Bistro?
- It's kind of complicated,
but it's like a small restaurant
that's not really cheap though.
- Not so cheap, but not so expensive.
- Uh-huh.
- And it's usually French.
- Yes.
- So it's small informal restaurant.
- Yeah, Bistro. - Mm-hmm.
- Okay, so our third phrase for
today is not all that crazy about.
- Not all that crazy about.
- I'm not all that crazy about.
- Okay, again, kind of a
funny phrase, but we've got
some examples that will help
you understand the meaning.
- Example one.
- Do you want to go
shopping with me tomorrow?
- I'm not all that crazy about shopping.
I don't like spending money.
- Example two.
- I'm not crazy about jazz music.
Can I change this one?
- So this is just a really polite way
of saying you don't like something.
- Exactly.
- But now the opposite
of this would be tasty.
- Tasty.
- That's our fourth word.
- It's tasty, tasty.
- So when something is tasty, it's good.
- It's good. - Like delicious.
- Delicious. - Yeah.
- You know what, in
English we almost never say,
the food is delicious, but we always say, - It's really tasty.
- Yes.
- This is really tasty. - Yes, okay.
- Tasty.
And our last phrase for language
takeaway in the mood for.
- In the mood for, in the mood for.
- Let's listen to some
examples of this phrase
and we'll understand the
meaning a little bit better.
- Example one.
- We always eat hamburgers for dinner.
I'm in the mood for something different.
- Example two.
- Let's watch a movie.
How about Texas Chancellor massacre?
- I am not in the mood for a horror movie.
- So if I'm in the mood for something,
I feel like doing or eating or watching.
- Yeah, it means you wanna do that now.
- Yeah.
- I'm in the mood for.
- Okay.
Some great language we just looked at,
and I think it's time for us to
listen to the dialogue a second time.
- Do you two have any
plans for the evening?
- We were thinking of checking
out a restaurant in the neighborhood.
Do you have any suggestions?
- I know this really nice Italian place.
The food is fantastic,
and the decor is beautiful.
I'd recommend giving it a try.
- Actually, I'm not all that
crazy about Italian food.
I'm in the mood for
something a bit lighter.
- In that case, I know
a great little bistro.
They make a really tasty seafood platter.
The fish is outstanding.
- It sounds fantastic, but
I'm allergic to seafood, so.
- Okay, well, let me think.
Oh, I know this great little place.
It's just a hole in the wall, but they
do the most amazing sandwiches.
You've got to give them a try.
- Ella, you took me there last time I
visited, and I got food poisoning, remember?
- Okay, some really great
and useful phrases there,
and I know you want to talk about
specifically some of these phrases.
- Yes, today's lesson is all about
making recommendations, right?
- Right.
- So let's look at some useful
phrases in fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
- So in the dialogue, we heard a
great way of asking for a suggestion.
- That's right.
- Let's listen.
- Do you have any suggestions?
- So that's how you would
ask for a suggestion, or you
can say something else
like, do you have any ideas?
- Yeah, or you might say,
do you have any thoughts?
- Okay, so that's asking for a suggestion.
- Yep.
- In response to this, you
can say something like this.
- I'd recommend giving it a try.
I'd recommend giving it a try.
We also heard another phrase
that we use for giving suggestions.
- You can give them a try.
- You've got to give them a try.
- So these two phrases are great.
I'd recommend, or you
gotta give them a try.
- Yeah.
- Great ways of suggesting.
- Yes.
- Now, what's really important here is
the pronunciation of these words, right?
- Yeah, you'll notice that we
don't say I would recommend.
- Right.
- Use the contraction,
I'd, I'd, I'd, I'd recommend.
- I'd recommend.
- Similarly, in the
phrase, you have got to,
we shorten that to say, you gotta.
- You gotta, you gotta give them a try.
- You gotta, you know what, guys?
If you can shorten your
phrases like this, if you can push
the sounds together, you'll
sound a lot more natural, hey?
- And also you'll be able to understand
because in movies, or in shows, they will
never say, you have got to give them a try.
- Yeah.
- So if you know how to use this
form, you'll understand what they need.
- Exactly.
- Okay, great.
- Well, why don't we listen
to the dialogue a third time,
and you'll hear some of these
contractions in the dialogue.
(upbeat music)
- Do you two have any
plans for the evening?
We were thinking of checking out
a restaurant in the neighborhood.
Do you have any suggestions?
- I know there's really nice Italian place.
The food is fantastic,
and the decor is beautiful.
I'd recommend giving it a try.
- Actually, I'm not all that
crazy about Italian food.
I'm in the mood for
something a bit lighter.
- In that case, I know
a great little bistro.
They make a really tasty seafood platter.
The fish is outstanding.
- It sounds fantastic, but
I'm allergic to seafood, so.
- Okay, well, let me think.
- Oh, I know this great little
place is just a hole in the wall,
but they do the most amazing sandwiches.
You can't give them a try.
- Ella, you took me there last time I
visited, and I got food poisoning, remember?
- Okay, great dialogue, and Erica,
I know that you have some
food poisoning stories for us.
- I don't know about stories, but I've
definitely had food poisoning before.
One of the worst times
that I ever had food
poisoning was when I
was traveling in Morocco.
- Okay.
- I had some really amazing orange juice,
really fresh squeeze that day in
the morning, and then I got on a bus.
- Okay.
- I think you can see where this is going.
(laughing)
- Yeah, so I was on the bus, and
then I started to feel really sick,
and I was just hoping and
hoping and hoping that the bus
ride would be over soon,
but unfortunately it wasn't.
- Oh no.
- All I can say is that I
was sick, and all I can say
is that I was pretty sick
and really, really unhappy.
- Yeah, I bet.
Well, that's very strange that you
got sick from orange juice, huh?
- Well, yeah, maybe it was with
some dirty water or something like that.
I don't know, it was just,
it was a terrible situation.
- Yeah, it's always complicated when
you're traveling to other countries,
it could be the water, it could
be the way they prepare things.
- Yeah, yeah, food poisoning.
- Guys, I hope that you
don't get food poisoning.
- And if you have any
food poisoning stories,
it would be great
for you to share them.
- Yes, at our website, EnglishPod.com.
- And we'll see you
there to answer all your
questions and comments,
but now we have to go.
- Okay, guys, thanks for listening.
- We'll see you there.
- Bye-bye.
(upbeat music)
[BLANK_AUDIO]